<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Kevin Wang&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Kevin Wang&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Robotic Ultrasound Mammography</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/co-robotic-ultrasound-mammography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/co-robotic-ultrasound-mammography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem&#34;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 40 million screenings are performed each year and around 6 million of those tests result in a the patient being called back to the office for further screening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotic system to autonomously move across the patient&amp;rsquo;s breasts after the X-Ray images are taken and acquire Ultrasound images of any regions of concern that may be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PlDYHuM19AU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hemodynamic Optimization with Novel Surgical Method</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/fontan-surgery-revision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/fontan-surgery-revision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balanced hepatic flow distribution (HFD) into pulmonary arteries (PA) is a key outcome variable in Fontan physiology to prevent pulmonary arteriovenous malformation. A convergent total cavopulmonary connection (CCPC) is a novel method of converging the superior/inferior vena (SVC/IVC) cava flows to manipulate and balance HFD; however, the influence of geometry has not been characterized. In this study, we investigated variations in CCPC with computational fluid dynamics (CFD) to determine its ability to control HFD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four cardiac magnetic resonance imaging datasets of Fontans were included. The Fontan was segmented and native conduit was removed. CCPC designs were created, with superior limb (connected to SVC) inserting into inferior limb (connected to IVC) at 5 angles along transverse plane (from 0° in AP to 60° in RAO). Both native and CCPC designs were evaluated by CFD under steady-state conditions, with SVC/IVC/outflow boundary conditions provided by phase contrast measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All four cases had a CCPC design with balanced HFD into pulmonary arteries (52±4% into left PA vs. 65±27% in native design). In
general, changing the RAO angulation of superior limb insertion affected streaming of SVC flow into right PA, thereby adjusting hepatic flow from IVC into left PA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a CCPC design, HFD can be adjusted by the angulation of superior limb insertion. CCPC is a potential solution to controlling the balance of HFD in Fontan flow .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Line Holography</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/holograpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/holograpm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hologram is a method of optical imagery, where, as opposed to a classic photograph which captures the intensities of an object, a hologram captures the intensities and phase of an object. That is to say, a hologram captures information regarding the entire object, and can thus reconstruct a true 3D representation of that object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to construct an in line holographic imaging setup and capture amplitude and phase information for an object. After this capture is complete, the hologram will be digitally reconstructed, and displayed on a monitor to illustrate multiple focal lengths with a single image capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surgical Tool to Prepare Subtalar Joint for TTC Arthrodesis</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Autoencoders for Dimensionality Reduction in Radiomics</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;fff&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modelling for Targeted Drug Delivery</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreational Clusters in Toronto</title>
      <link>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/skin-cancer-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://KevinWang905.gituhb.io/Kevin_Portfolio/project/skin-cancer-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Toronto_skyline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Toronto Skyline&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;toronto-recreation-clusters&#34;&gt;Toronto Recreation Clusters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the provincial capital of Ontario, Toronto is a prominent hub for its residents as well as the millions of tourists that visit per year. From nightlife to shopping to the arts, every corner of Toronto is packed with sites to visit and scenery to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toronto is a city full of exploration for tourists and opportunity for the entrepreneur. Due to the large amount of existing establishments, it may be difficult for an entrepreneur to decide on where to base their business. Where should they build a shopping center? A bar? What about a gym? On the other hand, a tourist only has a limited time to enjoy the city. Which districts should they visit based on their interests?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, I will mainly use the foursquare api. First, I will determine the districts of Toronto by scraping Wikipedia. From these determined districts, I will use their longitude and latitude to search for venues within a 500m radius. Using the category of the found venues, I plan to cluster the districts of Toronto and visualize them in an interactive map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;libraries&#34;&gt;Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project required the use of a few libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Folium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Folium is a library used to generate interactive maps. This will be used to visualize the neighbourhood locations in Toronto as well as the final clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Soup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful soup is a library used to scrape websites. This will be used to scrape wikipedia for the postal codes of the Toronto neighbourhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NumPy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy is a libary used to handle data in a vectorized manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandas is a library used for data analysis. This will be used to create dataframes for the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matplotlib is a library used for creating static, animated, and interactive visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sklearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sklearn is a library used for machine learning. This will be used to cluster the neighbourhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scraping-wikipedia&#34;&gt;Scraping Wikipedia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the BeautifulSoup library, the wikipedia page for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_postal_codes_of_Canada:_M&#34;&gt;Canadian postal codes starting with M&lt;/a&gt; was scraped for information on postal codes, boroughs, and neighbourhoods. This information was used in conjunction with a list of longitudes and latitudes of said codes to create a dataframe of the neighbourhoods and their coordinates. The head of this dataframe is pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Long_lat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Toronto Coordinates&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-venues&#34;&gt;Finding Venues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After isolating the boroughs in Toronto, the Foursquare api was used to find the types of venues present in each neighbourhood. The function getNearbyVenues_Overall was created to find the number of each type of venue present in each neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This function was used for each neighbourhood and results in the following dataframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Venues.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Toronto Venues&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dataframe was visualized with a bar graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bar1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is apparent that event venues are considerably more rare and not present in the majority of neighbourhoods. Therefore, due to their low number, the event venue category will be removed from the analysis. The resulting dataset is visualized in the bar graph below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Bar2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clustering&#34;&gt;Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the KMeans function from the SkLearn library, the Toronto neighbourhoods were clustered with a k of 2 to 30. For each of these sets of clusters, the inertia and silhouette score was calculated and graphed. This allowed the use of the elbow method to determine the optimal number of clusters: 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;elbow.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clustering the neighbourhoods into 5 clusters yeilded the following cluster distribution. The venue categories used were: Arts and Entertainment, Nighlife, Outdoors and Recreations, and Shops and Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cluster_graphs.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These clusters were then plotted using folium onto a map of Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;clusters.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon inspection, &lt;strong&gt;Clusters 0 and 1&lt;/strong&gt; are quite similar, with only a difference in the percentage of Arts and Entertainment. Looking at the map generated, this distinction does make sense as neighbourhoods in cluster 0 are located closer to downtown Toronto. As a tourist, these areas may be of note if nightlife is not a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster 2&lt;/strong&gt; is noticably prominent, boasting a large percentage of venues categorized as Outdoors and Recreation. However, as a tourist, these neighbourhoods (Rosedale and Summerpark East) are residential neighbourhoods and therefore may not be very interesting to visit. As an entrepreneur, this area should be approached with caution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster 3&lt;/strong&gt; has the highest percentage of venues classified as a shop or service. These areas may be of note to entrepreneurs due to their distance from downtown Toronto which can lead to lower property prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;Cluster 4&lt;/strong&gt; is the most well rounded of clusters. It has an equal distribution of all 4 venue types. The neighbourhoods in this cluster are grouped in downtown Toronto. This cluster is recommended if tourists wish to spend an entire day exploring, as well as enjoy the nightlife offered. For entrepreneurs, though this area does see higher traffic than the other clusters, property prices here are also higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further analysis would provide much more clarity for each cluster. The addition of property prices for each cluster would be beneficial to both entrepreneurs as well as people moving into the city. In each category of venue, there are additional types of venues. Therefore, for further clarity, each cluster can be grouped into subclusters based on venue type. Traffic to each cluster would also be useful for entrepreneurs looking to open a business. This traffic would include the amount of people visiting, mean income, and if possible, the percentage of money spent in each category of venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this analysis yeilded a promising foothold for further research. The most balanced neighbourhoods were in cluster 4, located in downtown Toronto. Moving further away from downtown, the other clusters generally had much fewer nighlife and arts and entertainment venues, but more outdoors, recreation, and shopping venues. The exception to this is cluster 0 which had fewer nighlife venues, but maintained the amount of arts and entertainment venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
